chapter one of Black Beauty this is a LibriVox recording all
LibriVox recordings are in the public domain for more information or to
volunteer please visit librivox.org recording by Cory Samuel Black Beauty his Grooms and
companions The autobiography of a horse translated from THE original eoin by Anna
Su Part one chapter 1 My Early Home The first place that I can well
remember was a large pleasant meadow with a pond of clear water in it. Some
shady trees leaned over it, and rushes and water lies grew at the deep end. Over
the hedge on one side we looked into a plowed field, and on the other we looked
over a gate at our master's house, which stood by the
roadside; at the top of the meadow was a grove of fur trees, and at the bottom a
running brook overhung by a steep bank. While I was young I lived upon my
mother's milk, as I could not eat grass.
In the daytime I ran by her side, and at night I lay down close by
her. When it was hot we used to stand by
the pond in the shade of the trees, and
when it was cold we had a nice warm shed near the
grove. As soon as I was old enough to eat
grass my mother used to go out to work in the daytime, and come back in the
evening. There were six young Cults in the meadow besides me; they were older
than I was; some were nearly as large as grown-up horses. I used to run with them,
and had great fun; we used to gallop all together round and round the field as
hard as we could go. Sometimes we had rather rough play, for they would frequently bite and kick
as well as gallop. One day, when there was a good
deal of kicking, my mother winned to me to come to her, and then she said: “I wish
you to pay attention to what I'm going to say to you. The Cults who live here
are very good Cults but they are cart horse Cults and of course they have not
learned manners. You have been well bred and well born your father has a great
name in these parts, and your grandfather won the cup 2 years at the new market
races; your grandmother had the sweetest temper of any horse I ever knew you and
I think you have never seen me kick or bite. I hope you will grow up gentle and
good, and never learn bad ways; do your work with a good will, lift your feet up
well when you trot, and never bite or kick even in play.” I have never forgotten my mother's
advice; I knew she was a wise old horse, and our master thought a great deal of
her. Her name was Duchess, but he often called her Pet
pet Our master was a good, kind man. He gave us good food, good lodging, and kind
words; he spoke as kindly to us as he did to his little children. We were all fond
of him, and my mother loved him very much.
When she saw him at the gate she would
Nay with joy, and trot up to him. He would
pat and stroke her and say, “Well, old Pet, and how is your little
I was a dull black, so he called me then he would give me a piece of bread,
which was very good, and sometimes he bought a carrot for my
mother. All the horses would come to him, but I think we were his favorites. My
mother always took him to town on a market day in a light
gig. There was a plow boy Dick, who sometimes came into our field to pluck
blackberries from the hedge. When he had eaten all he wanted he would have what
he called fun with the Cults throwing stones and sticks at them to make them
gallop. We did not much mind him, for we could gallop off; but sometimes the stone
would hit and hurt us. One day he was at this game, and did not know that the
master was in the next field; but he was there, watching what was going on; over
the head she jumped in a snap, and catching Dick by the arm, he gave him
such a box on the ear as made him roar with the pain and
surprise. As soon as we saw the master we trotted up nearer to see what went on.
“Bad boy!” he said, “bad boy! to chase the colts. This is not the first time, nor the
second, but it shall be the last. There— —take your money and go home; I shall not
want you on my farm again.” So we never saw Dick anymore Old Daniel, the man who looked
after the horses, was just as gentle as our master, so we were well
off end of chapter 1